Okay. Good morning, good afternoon, good evening, everyone.
I hope you had a very nice Tuesday yesterday.
Hope you were inspired enough
to start creating your own documentation this week.
And we can start with the first tutorial on visual documentation.
First of all, I think I can introduce better myself.
My name is Claudia Simonelli. I'm an Italian designer, actually based now in
Jordan. I work here in the Crown Prince Foundation Makerspace, where I'm also the
local instructor for Fab Academy, and also at the general level in the academy, I
serve as communication manager.
I have a background in both project and communication design, so I think the skills
are very good to show you what I've prepared for you.
And let me share my screen.
I hope you can see better. So this presentation will be not very boring.
It will be full of visuals. We're going to talk about different things, starting
from what will be your best friend during the six months, but especially this week,
which is the Class Archive.
I will show you different documentations that have been also created during these
10 years of Fab Academy. Different tools, so you have different alternatives in
terms of processing techniques, and software to explore, especially in this first
phase of the academy. We're going to talk a little bit about AI, but also the
credits and the license. And I have also prepared at the end of the slides,
different resources in the list, so you can choose also different platforms that
are available online for you to browse information, to search open source features,
and et cetera. If you have questions, maybe it's better to tackle all of them at
once at the end of the session, and for now, you can put them in the chat.
As I was saying earlier, you can download already the software.
I prepared something in GIMP, so the workflow will be very much similar
in other software. In Fab Academy, we strongly promote the open source one.
So for example, Inkscape is very good also for next week for laser cutting, but
also to create logo and those kind of things. That's something that is vector.
And GIMP is the best alternative to Photoshop.
But of course, every year there is a lot of software that are still new and
released.
Okay, we move forward. So the Class Archive is how we refer to this website,
class.textile-academy.org. I think all of you yesterday at least had a peek
of this website that looks like this.
This is a website that is organized in a similar way of your web pages.
So it's like a platform that is being maintained by myself, Anastasia, Cecile, and
Julian. So we also work in a very similar way.
We create content that we commit, and we push to the server of Fabric Network.
In the session afterwards with Julian, he will be also deep diving more into the
markdown and your actual website.
For now, I just want to remind you where you can find yourself, your website, so
you have different ways to access the resources here.
One is on the top where you have participants.
So if you click on that, it's a shortcut for finding the current participant list,
and they are organized under the labs.
Or if you scroll a little bit down, you can find the participants across the
different years. So if you're also curious about somebody else's documentations,
maybe there's something that you want to see specifically, you can go back in time
and check the different assignments.
One other thing that I want to mention is that we have different tools.
On top you can see, click on the tools, and we have different software already
organized per week. So for example, we have different platform that we suggest for
you to explore, starting from today.
So for example, somebody was asking about Canva. Yeah, Canva is a very good one.
It's online, so you don't have also
to use your computer. You can rely on the app on the phone, on the app on the
tablet,
as well as the browser here. For the vector, we have our software as well as you
can see here on the side for the different weeks.
If you also
have some suggestion that you want to make, also feel free, and you can also put
them in the chat. So we will be very happy to add every year the new software,
especially if they are open source.
Yeah, so the other very useful resource for you and for these six months is the
handbook. Also, the handbook you can find in the Class Archive.
It looks
very similar also in this platform.
You can find for all the different selection of the assignments with the learning
outcomes, the objective. Everything is also here linked in the slides afterwards.
So everything is here interactive, at hand.
And of course, in the handbook is also written what you're asked to do to develop
your assignment. So starting from today, you have roughly six days.
So next Tuesday, we will be seeing already different participants from different
labs, and we're going to go through different documentation.
So from today onwards, you are asked to build your documentation website, so
describing yourself, your background, your previous works.
We are also very curious to see what you can bring to the course.
What was your background? What was your motivation to join this course?
We
expect you to add some reference and research based also on what interests you,
what you have done before. But also, one very important skill to learn for now is
to master, at least to get used to these tools, like work with Git, with what is
called version control, and what you're going to start today with Julian.
An extra point will be customize your website, but I think it will be also
wonderful. You can combine all these things so we can also see a bit of your
personality emerging from your content.
You can also find more
here in the handbook.
And let's start giving you some examples which I think they are very nice
documentation to have a look at. So here there is a different selection.
As you can see, we have one similar template for everyone.
It's actually the same, but every person every time customize in a completely
different way.
You have a template that is built in on Markdown, which is what Julian will
tackle mostly in the second part of today.
But it's also nice how sometimes you can add a little bit of HTML or other
languages to complement and expand the possibility of this language.
There's no great recipe, I think, for really making the best documentation,
but I think it's a combination of things. So I just have some tips.
Definitely, you have already a template, so you have some guidelines.
These guidelines for now are helping you to organize the content, because for this
week is not maybe a lot, but starting from next week, we also have machine, we also
have something to produce and fabricate.
You're going to have to deal with different information.
So getting to know already, for example, how to create a table with Markdown, with
HTML, doesn't matter.
Or how to organize information like specifications about materials, machine, but
also recipe,
is also that you have starting to deal with.
And also a nice way to do that is adding a little bit of yourself.
So adding a little bit of visuals, maybe, something aesthetic, and really make it
yours.
Talking about the markdown scenes we mentioned, I just wanted to tell you that
there's nothing that is that much complicated to learn, given also the short time.
There are many resources online, and I'm sure Julian will have definitely more to
show you. You can just Google Markdown cheatsheet, and you can find different
PDFs, pictures that really give you this kind of summary, where you can see
there is not a lot that you need to know. Everything is basically here.
So these are like the symbol and small syntax that will help you to style your
text.
I want to show you different examples, how different people also across these years
make this documentation really theirs.
One, say, inspiration is also mood boards that Viviana, for example, we used.
She was very much inspired by architecture, so you can see different ways also to
make collage and organize the content.
All of them, in the end, were also nice because they've been reflected in their
final outcomes, in the assignments, but also in the final project.
There's, I think, a lot of fashion designers here, and I always appreciate the way
the visual, the pictures get combined with handwritten text, but also sketches.
And I also invite you to have a look later at the work of Stephanie Santos.
There is also very nice documentation of Alberte also dealing with the white space.
So not focusing on completely
filling all the gaps in your documentation, but also leave some air in between the
pictures. This is also where the references she had during the first week.
And I also like, for example, I think Dinesh probably used Canva to organize,
create also color palette
for the projects. I also enjoy very much the work of Alessia Pasquini and also the
different ways that she were combining colors with textures, materials
together.
You don't have to remember all these names.
I'm going to give you the slides, and all of them are already linked.
And of course, some people still like to take notes by hand or digitally
on the tablet, like here. So I also very much enjoy the work of Elsa Gill.
So for every week, she was sketching the workflow and recipes, for example.
And here you can see how she broke down all this big chunk of information starting
from GitLab, and this is all the understanding and the workflow that you will be
actually learning in these days. A lot
of people also enjoy very much drawing.
So this is also the drawings that have been digitalized later on, like in
applications like Inkscape, Illustrator, et cetera.
But it's worth to have a look at the work of Lucchese DeLeon.
This was doing this beautiful works during the pandemic with his son, but also the
work of Isabelle a couple of years ago.
A completely different approach.
Here we have... You actually have in the template this kind of a matrix of
assignments where you have these kinds of blocks, where you have this placeholder,
a greenish picture. And it would be also nice if you could put some love there
and make it yours as well. So here are a couple of examples from Ainoa, that she
was also interested to exploring the
plant words. And also, I like the work of Aileen, when it was one big picture that
was split in different parts like a puzzle.
So every assignment was part of a bigger system.
Of course, we saw yesterday the work of Svetlana.
So welcome to the colorful world of Svetlana.
It was also nice to see the different colors applied per topic, per assignment, and
also the work
of Maddy Olsen, who was combining the picture towards kind of the outcome with the
text.
Sometimes you may need to create some infographics, and these are also very nice
references. And when you saw Aliso a couple of years ago, blocks also can be
generated with vectors and recombined in different ways.
And also very much enjoy, again, the work of Annabel, who was drawing by
hand and then digitalized later on
her
kind of schematics with a bit of visual that also make very clear the workflow, the
recipes, and the different information. So very pleasant to see.
One of my favorite is also the work of Alberte, and you can see...
You saw yesterday the video about the seaweed, and you can see the whole material
research also explored as a final project.
So you can see how the visuals here really make clear the content and all the
different information variations that she had to document.
A lot of people like to talk, and nowadays I think it's a very
common practice that we have with the phone.
So you can also include, for example, your MP3 file inside your documentation and
bring it back here, for example, to introduce the assignment yourself.
So it's also a way to make it very personal.
I like here the example of Sara because she also put it transcription in case you
cannot hear, and you can also see how she actually did this inside the
website. There is a big disclaimer here, and you will not like it.
No GIFs are allowed anymore in Fab Academy.
We used to have those allowed, and unfortunately, we lost a lot of content.
GIFs are also something that is very heavy, very heavy to load, and very heavy on
the server. So, since a couple of years, GIFs are not allowed in Fab Academy, and
we're very strict on this.
Still, if you really think that it's worth to make a GIF and you really want to
have something moving, something interactive,
you can explore this website, which is called... It's online.
It's called ezgif.com, and allows you to create just an
MP4 file, just like a video format that you can loop over and over
like it was a GIF. In this case, you can really control and compress it as much as
possible. So for example, talking about the size, we don't want something that is
bigger than one megabyte.
Moving to the online resources that you already have at your hand.
Some people like to personalize the colors for the web pages.
So a couple of nice resources can be found also in Adobe Color.
All of these are for free. They're there. You can check the codes.
You can also copy-paste all of them and use in your own way.
You can produce secondary colors and et cetera. There are so many nowadays.
And of course, also Canva. The moment you add one picture, you're able to extract
the exact colors of the different elements.
As we were saying earlier, Canva is very much used also in Fab Academy.
You can create now booklets, use the templates that are already created by the
community. There is a lot of free designs for you to use, to save, and to
customize. So yes, definitely, if you're already working with that, you can keep
it, especially to remove the background and those kind of things.
Canva is very much useful.
Of course, if you're a fashion designer especially, you may know Pinterest.
So Pinterest is also very nice platform for doing some research to get inspired
by different people, different works.
Everybody can put their content on Pinterest, and there are real projects that
belong to people. So always remember to credit the pictures that come out of this
platform,
unless you have the license that the works belong to you.
We also have an account on Pinterest, and every year we put a lot of projects, so
you can also add your own things and tag Fab Academy.
A couple of alternatives for copyleft.
I want to say copyright-free pictures are also on Splash.
This is a very nice resource, and very beautiful pictures available also in
HD, in the best definition possible.
So you can just write keyword here and browse all the different possibilities.
Another one is like Pixels, and it also works for videos, and you can just write
wood and a lot of things that are related to wood, including the colors will
appear. And also here, you don't need to credit the authors.
An alternative to Canva, but this is only obviously for making collage online, is
also called Photo Collage and allows you to create different styles.
There are different templates for collage, just in a matter of seconds that
Actually already compressed the moment you download them.
Yes, because compressing pictures is also mandatory, and there are many software
that do that. And if you're a little bit lazy, of course, you can use WhatsApp.
So you can WhatsApp yourself with all the heavy pictures that nowadays phone
create, and then you can download all the pictures at once at a very low
resolution. So the best platform, for me, is still Online
PNG Tools. It's like an online website.
It's very easy and straightforward, so there are different options that you can
choose from. And of course, you can remove the background as well, and most
important, compress the picture in different ways.
If you would like to work in bulk, so delivering the whole folder and work at the
same time at the different pictures because you feel like you don't have a lot of
time, there is also this platform that I suggest where you can add
as many pictures as you want, and the same setting is applied to all.
So you can export to about seven different file formats.
It can read from PNG to GIF to WebP and everything all at once.
Of course, there is a lot of nowadays AI-powered online tools that also help
you to remove the background, for example.
They work well. Maybe they just have some limitations in terms of how many pictures
you can work on here. Remove.bg is a good one, does a good job.
Or you can do this by yourself, which is also a very good skill to master.
Of course, in Canva. I don't remember if you need Canva Pro to do that, but Canva
also does a very good job in removing the background, even
though the picture is challenging.
For example, you have hair and also Canva is very good at that. AI.
So in Fab Academy, we want to promote the use of AI,
like a responsible tool. So you need to learn how to use AI
responsibly. That means that it's very good as a tool nowadays, and
all of us at least once we've made advantage of that.
So if it's used as a supporting tool for, example, creating variations
of projects, supporting the exploration, it's good.
Definitely help us to prototype faster, to expand in the direction, but also to
optimize the process and most of the time.
You must credit and also write whenever you use that in your assignments.
But we were very strict on this. So, you have to do the thinking first,
to not delegate this, that I think is also the most beautiful part of creating
something. So exploring the concept,
getting back to the different references, and we don't want AI to do that for us.
We don't want a machine to do this for us.
So never use AI for your inspirational references.
And remember that those things define who you are and what you like.
I have an example from Dinesh. You saw his final project yesterday in a video, the
one who was exploring the concept of 3D printing applied to couture.
This project was many years ago, actually, when AI was still at the very
beginning.
And it's interesting how Dinesh was actually sketching by hand the different
variations of this dress that he wanted to make, and then he was creating a prompt
that was able to take those things to the next level.
And here you can see, and this was done in Midjourney, how the different variations
also probably contributed to
the final garment.
There is also here some nice reference.
Hala, you can find this video back because it's linked to the documentation.
She had also, for example, for the code, it will not be allowed to copy-paste
directly things from any ChatGPT, Claude, or any AI in general.
So it's also nice that
she created the ChatGPT
the moment it's being used.
So to recap this part, it's very much forbidden to do direct copy-paste,
to do the research in ChatGPT and any of the AI, to also rephrase the
documentation, because this is not an English course, so it's better to read
something that comes from yourself than something that is all the same.
And we really can see nowadays that all the text sound alike but also look alike.
So the machine-made text is something very obvious, and I really invite you not to
do that.
And really, there is a lot of documentation, not just in Fab Academy.
We can read these things everywhere on the website, blogs, and everything, and
they're all the same.
If you feel like you need to fix some English, I recommend you Grammarly.
It's also AI-powered, not invasive.
This has been existing since
ChatGPT was born, and it doesn't restructure completely your content, your
text.
Another problem that we have relying on the AI is that
usually it feeds us with false information.
Those things are very much misleading, and of course, AI also tends to
merge different websites together to invent citations and also fabricate
completely false information. So always double-check the fact and always
double-check the real website, the real data sheet, the real paper, and the real
author.
Talking about ownership, we move to credit and license.
So in Fab Academy, as well as in the Fablab Network, we believe in the spirit of
openness and collaboration where the knowledge is exchanged.
So I don't know if you paid attention to your webpage already and footer.
At the very bottom, it is written, "Creative Common License, Attribution and
Commercial, International." So that means that whatever you produce, as you make,
is released with this license. That basically allows people, everybody that comes
to your documentation, wants to get inspired from your work, to share the content,
also redistribute with the same license, but also they are able to adapt those,
remix, and build upon.
So you can see here in detail with attribution, of course.
So everybody needs to credit the author properly, providing also a link to the
work. And of course, this is non-commercial.
So all of these things that you have will not help no one to make a business out of
those.
Both the project, the documentation, and whatever it is that you put on the
website.
How to credit properly. Pictures and projects done.
We have here a few examples. I think it's
very nice how Luz Boget here, for example, was crediting a picture of herself that
was made in collaboration with another person.
So in the description of the picture, and actually in all the pictures that she
uploaded to the website, you can see a small tag writing exactly what is the
picture, sometimes accompanied by the date and the people and the photographer.
And also here in the mood board next to it, you can see all the different pictures,
the title with attribution. So this is the right way to do that.
And a picture that is not accompanied by the author, the ownership will not be also
allowed to stay on the website alone. There is many ways to do that.
We talked about collage, so also you're free to explore this at a different level
the way you like. As long as this information is written on the documentation.
If you really want to do a good job, you also can include the photographer.
That is also often forgotten
Let's move to the media editing. So in your documentations from the next week of
digital body, you are asked also to upload files.
Files is a general word. In Fab Academy, it means both PDFs, vector
files,
booklets, slides, the Grasshopper definition, and of course, 3D models.
So we've been talking about compression, and we will be talking about that for a
long time. So PDFs also must be uploaded first to the Git but must be compressed.
And again, there is a limitation on the use of Google Slide and Canva
embed only. That means that you can upload those as long as the real source,
like the real PDF, is uploaded as well to the repository.
The PDF you're going to see later on probably with Julian is a link
in Markdown. So the way to add it is pretty straightforward.
Inside your template, if you have it already navigated a little bit, you might have
seen something like this, which is already a PDF viewer that helps you
to visualize the PDF and scroll it in this vertical format.
You can see here an example of a thesis as a result of the final project.
That is something that you will be doing next year.
But also you can see here the code, how this looks like in Markdown.
So there is a path, there is a files folder, and your PDF that is called
booklet_compressed is located inside this folder.
Speaking about the booklet, but this is not something that you have to worry about
now.
We have many booklets that we will be also revealing that are made in these
many years of academy during the next months.
And one that I want to mention, since we talked about this material research, but
also the different infographics, is this work from Alberte
that she developed in Iceland in 2022, and this also was made entirely in Canva.
So she already had everything in one place, and that made very easy to integrate
them all together in one document.
So yes, compressing PDFs is mandatory, and you can use
different apps to do that literally in 10 seconds.
We put those in your template as a tip that you can remove.
So you have already the links over there, but just to clarify this again, you can
use, for example, ilovepdf.com. You can drag and drop your PDF, and you can
see that from 60 megabyte, this became something like one in just 20 seconds.
So there is no excuse on this.
Another platform is still online, free, no limits, that you can use
is PDF24 Tools, and it works in the similar way.
So you can also decide the image quality for the different pages and have
a great result in term of compression.
If you feel like
you want, for example, now to
include your portfolio, you can also use one of the other software and platform
that are available online. One of those is Heizeen, and you can
embed the code. So you click on share, and this will be the same workflow that you
do for the videos, and you just embed this.
It's your portfolio, so it's not part of Fab Academy, and you're allowed to include
it like this.
Sorry.
So how to upload the fabrication files, whatever they are, and the different
formats.
So the 3D models and the Grasshopper definitions also need to be uploaded to the
Git.
How to do that? Sometimes we deal with
files that are very heavy. So the best way and the best practice will be creating a
zip folder on your computer and uploading this as it is, containing the different
files to the Git.
There is also linked in the documentation a tutorial on how to do this on
the Mac, which is be just selecting the things that you want to compress, and
right-click and selecting compress.
In a similar way in Windows, you just have to do send to a compressed folder.
Very easy, and it literally takes five seconds, and this is what will save a lot of
space in your website, because there is also a certain space, and you shouldn't
have a very big
size.
We also have some examples in the template now for the 3D model viewers, and these
are also third software that you can use to visualize your 3D
models.
Again, your 3D model needs to be first added, example as STL, inside
your zipped folder and linked to the documentation.
But this is something extra for your own portfolio.
So it's something that you can include for platforms like Sketchfab and do, again,
embed the code or, for example, p3d.in.
How to include a video? So videos are something that are very, very big normally.
And the best way to do that, especially if you have a short movie or a work that
you've done before in a video format and as an interview that you want to include
in your documentation, the best way is to have them uploaded on YouTube or Vimeo
and then click on share, copy, paste the embed code.
It's not the link that you see on top.
It's this embed code that allows you to have this kind of window with the video
playing in the documentation. You already have an example of that, so there is
nothing to learn here. It will be just direct copy-paste. Same thing on Vimeo.
That means that if you also have, for example, next week, a very nice
laser cutting process or you're assembling this mannequin, it would be maybe very
nice to do a video. So you can upload this first either on YouTube, Vimeo, or
whatever other platforms that you know, and then you can do click
on share, get the embed code, and copy-paste it back in the documentation.
We're moving to photo editing. So this is the basic.
This is very useful information and something to know as the base for the next
weeks, especially when we talk about fabrication, digital fabrication.
So the difference between the raster and the vector is just the resolution.
So we know pictures. Pictures are also called bitmaps.
So they are images that are made of different pixels that are these kind of squares
that are full of colors. So what happens here the moment you zoom?
You zoom in, keep on zooming, you have open more pixels, you encounter more
squares, and the picture sometimes is blurry.
The vector is something opposite.
So the vectors are actually equations that are mathematically generated points and
shapes and paths, and they look like this.
So the more you zoom in, nothing changes.
That's why they also have different formats.
So when we talk about vector, we talk about, for example,
SVGs, PDFs,
EPS, any of these. And when we talk about pictures, of course, we all know JPEG,
PNG, GIF, HEIF, and so on.
So we also have different software, right?
We said earlier we have GIMP as an alternative free and open source to the most
famous one, which is Photoshop. And we have an alternative for also the very
famous one, Illustrator, which is Inkscape.
But of course, there is other countless platform that you can use.
So these are just two suggestions, but you're free to explore those,
yours, and also many others.
Just to clarify, because this, as we said, is very important to be applied also
in general to digital fabrication, and this software will be very much useful,
especially the vector one, for cutting a machine, for producing things that will be
3D-printed later on, especially if you combine this workflow with the 3D modeling
software or something that definitely will be cut either by a laser or a CNC.
So for cutting those things, we need vector files, but we also need
closed loops that are made of vector points, shapes, and so on.
So also the software will be your best friends for next time.
We will not be talking today about the laser cutter.
You also have next week to explore the topic deeper.
So those are
software as well that can be used for resizing the pictures, so scaling down,
editing, and also manipulating at a general level.
You can also optimize your picture if you just go on top of image, scale image.
We can also do in a demo later on, depends on how many people will be asking
that. Resize scale and optimize is the basic and also very much useful for you to
compress the files.
I also promote GIMP because I know that there is this nice plugin that's called
GIMP, and you can download it from here and you can use.
So you can apply all the different manipulations, whatever they are, including, for
example, converting to grayscale and increasing the threshold,
the brightness to all of them together.
I think it was one in the tutorials I gave many years ago, so I also don't
want to repeat the same thing, but it's something that you can find in the class
archive.
So in the end, these are the best practices to conclude this part.
So
you need to resize and optimize your pictures for the web.
And when we talk about computers and web in general, we talk about the resolution
of the monitor, which is 72 DPI. Doesn't matter if it's the screen of the phone,
the computer or the TV. And let's say, as a general rule, you can remember
to compress your pictures so all of them, they are maximum 100,
150 KB is also accepted. And of course, most important, remember to
credit the pictures. It's also a good practice to credit your own pictures.
So next time a person goes to your website, it will be easier for them to credit
yourself.
We move to the media production. These are also
different examples from different alumni.
And what I want to highlight here is that you can invest a little bit of your time,
since what you're building from today is actually a portfolio.
A lot of people got many opportunities, like job opportunities, different
connections.
And it's very good to invest this time that you have to curate also aesthetically
your page. So this for me is a very nice example to show on how Luz Bogas
photoshooted the material. The material is also sometimes translucent, so it's also
very hard to picture them correctly.
So if you have a setup at home where you can benefit from natural light or lab
lights or the ring that is very much nowadays common,
you can also bring these things to the lab at your house and create a setup
that stays for different months. So every week before uploading those things to the
documentation, you can spend 10 minutes to curate a little bit this part.
So here are different options, and you can see where you can also have per topic,
but also
for the different outcomes and projects.
So here, for example, if you want to make something like a booklet with
instructions, it's very good to take a picture, for example, every time on the same
angle from the top to show all the details.
And also you can find more on this documentation. This is a kit.
Also everybody can make it. So it's very nice how the booklet really helps and
guides you visually from the pictures.
So the text is also minimal. This is something that
is done in the third week, so open source circular fashion.
It's very nice how the pictures can also reflect the kind of materials, the
texture, the shape, and also, for example, having a simple photoshoot where you
have a person interacting with the object really communicates what is it for.
So for example, if you remove the hand here, maybe you wouldn't say that it's a
bag.
This is for next week. So
you will be seeing different examples of mannequins and other creations in the
lecture. And this is one picture about one of those that's been produced in
Barcelona in 2021. And I really like also the choice,
let's say black and white, to complement and to really
highlight the geometries that are created here with the laser.
And also a completely different mannequin.
So you can see also a bit how you can contribute with the light to create this kind
of narrative around the project. And it's also a very beautiful
outcome from the work of Alessia Pasquini.
If you work with bio materials, you can also create this kind of lab space where
it's more contextualized. You have different tools, you have a clean environment,
so you can also invest some minutes to clean the stains and remove a little bit the
mess.
All of these things, all of these pictures mostly have been taken by the phone, by
the students without the help of a professional person.
So you can also see how the results are different
and also very well made, I would say.
We have also some students that had the chance to work with some models or people
that they knew that could model for the different outcomes.
This is the work of Eduardo Loredo.
This is our final project collection, but still it's worth to get some inspirations
for these months.
And of course, you can nowadays fabricate different tools to support your phone, to
support your camera. A camera is even better.
Just remember to compress the pictures at the very end.
And as a rule of thumb, of course,
the natural light is always more useful, as well as preferable.
Try to avoid to upload pictures that really mean nothing, pictures that are blurry
or they don't mean much in term of content.
In terms of videos, the
horizontal ones are still preferable.
Still because our computer, TV are also in the same format.
And we have also different resources when it comes to create the tools.
We are makers. We all like to create our own tools in case we have time, because
this is also not a priority.
We can use any of the files that have been produced.
Yeah, somebody raised their hand.
Yes. I just wanted to mention that if you want to show
the screen of the computer,
do not take a picture of the computer with your phone.
Just make a screenshot of the computer.
Yeah. Thanks for saying this because sometimes it's also not too obvious.
But there is a shortcut if you don't know.
Every Mac, every Windows has its own keys, and you can just take a screenshot
within the computer. So what I see here, but yeah.
I also added two questions in the chat.
Okay, great. So here, for example, Luz was not satisfied by the different stands
that she found online, so she made her own and she released this open source.
So from here you can download it, but you can also remake it because this is
still done 2018, so many years passed.
There's a couple of platforms that are worth to have a look where you can find not
just light boxes to take pictures, but also tutorials.
These are done by, in general, the making community worldwide.
So you just put a keyword and you get different resources.
There is a lot of nice light boxes that are easy to replicate in terms of projects
within 30 minutes, and usually they use very cheap and accessible materials.
And one other platform is called Thingiverse.
I think most of you might have known also, it's very famous for 3D printing.
Here you can find SDL files that are ready to 3D print.
So if you have a lot of 3D printers, maybe it's worth to just 3D print a couple of
the stands and then work in combination with the materials that you have at your
hand.
Going to the video production. So you also have some videos, again, in the
documentation, and you have some suggestions in terms of software or encoders.
Again, there are many, many platforms nowadays to make videos, TikToks and et
cetera. Lightworks is a popular one, which is open source.
These tools will also be useful for you to create your final project, so it's
better if you
give it a try during this first phase of the program.
CapCut is also a famous one, very intuitive and doesn't take a lot of time to get
to know the interface.
For the people that, of course, also have been knowing Premiere and Rush, of
course, we can say that Lightworks is the best alternative.
Also, in terms of interface, it's very similar.
And the most important one here is actually HandBrake.
This is an open source platform, which is also an application.
So it's a software that you can download for both Mac, Windows, et cetera.
And this is your compressor. So this is called encoding.
I'm talking about the video, and this allows you to convert your video also in
other formats, but with different settings that are here
suggested. And in a matter of two clicks, you can really compress your video, so
you can scale it down from being 1 gigabyte to 10 megabytes.
It's very powerful, very useful, and very easy to use.
Sometimes you may feel like you don't have enough videos you made yourself, so you
need to add some extra footage. Here on Pexels, as we saw earlier, we also have
some options to including free videos and clips.
So again, just put a keyword. You don't need to credit the author.
So these are all copyright-free videos.
And Pixabay as well.
Same with the music. The music is something we will be insisting very much next
year when you have to make your own final project video.
The music is something that needs to be as well, of course, open source, and there
is a lot of alternatives.
Sound libraries, music for every different vibe,
different
country. There is really a lot that every day is being generated.
So have a look at all the different resources that I put at the end of the
presentation because there is a lot to explore.
And of course, you can create your own.
Nowadays, you can also create your own sound, but of course, the voiceover, for
example, might come from you.
So for the video, I always say that the horizontal format is still preferable.
So in this case, the ratio would be 16 by 9, like one of the pictures for the
computer, full screen.
The videos, it's better if they are uploaded also in high resolution on Vimeo and
YouTube, I'm talking, so they also don't show up blurry.
Again, 72, 720 pixel is the minimum considered for the
resolution. Of course, 4K, 8K, and et cetera is even better.
Always remember to embed your video first and then copy-paste the embed code in the
web page.
Here, I will not go through this. I'll just give you the list as it is.
You can explore the footage. I've included some free
photography course. They're very short. Some, they're very good.
I think this one's still here by MoMA. There is some on Udemy.
There's a lot of free things that you can learn from different platforms, but also
institutions online. And here are the stock videos that you can benefit from for
free.
Okay, this is just one hour past. We're perfectly on time.
I don't mean to be very long while doing the demo.
Let me know
also if there's some questions, because I cannot see the chat when I stop screen
sharing for a bit. And
okay, there is only two questions. If you have more, you can also unmute yourself.
Okay, meanwhile, Anastasia has some questions.
So how many pixels you recommend for images?
Actually, I'm going to give you the slide.
So you can also go back.
I'm going to put them literally on the most.
You should be able to access all of them.
So to focus on the pixel is not important because you can just have one reference
or two. One for sure is the resolution.
So the more you increase the resolution, the bigger
and heavier also your picture will be.
And I usually
resize my pictures like 300 by whatever they are. So you can lock the ratio.
So you can just adjust one of the measurement, and then the other one will follow
accordingly.
Yeah, you can use... Exactly. There is many alternatives nowadays.
So YouTube audio library for
free copyright music.
AI to make my own music. Again, I think it would be nice to explore
first by yourself. It's something...
Because if you're interested in this, then maybe you also want to try first and
then use the AI not to cut the fun, but to increase the possibilities, maybe
to play with effect. In this sense, I think I would go more in this direction.
And a lot of people have been using AI for
optimizing the pictures like a professional photoshoot.
I think I stand in between.
I think it's fun. I personally like to get the challenge also to
try by myself, how can I make this picture as more professional as possible?
But I think
if this doesn't work, you can also try the AI version.
For example, if you want to upscale, sometimes the picture is in a very bad
resolution, and unfortunately, there is no time to repeat an assignment.
Yeah, I would say you can do upscale with Canva or with any of the platform online.
But in general, I don't feel like myself at least giving my own things that I make,
and I feed the AI with that because you don't control this, and they're part of a
bigger picture that you don't know, and we kind of lose ownership at the same
time. It's still not very clear, I think, in general, where all this content will
be one day. So I would prefer trying myself first, at least with the tools.
And nowadays, we have a lot of tools. Not like 20 years ago.
Now,
we have much to play with. It's just the time that is the biggest
constraint, I think.
I think there
was no other question.
I went a little bit fast because everything is written in the slides, and you can
just click and go back to the different projects. Also for the sake of time.
I included at the end of the slides what I was planning to demonstrate with the
software. If it's something that is not needed, also tell me so we can have a
longer break. But if you feel like, yeah, why not?
Let's do this in 10 minutes or something, we can do that.
Every year, we try to accommodate the different needs, and I know that in Fabrica
we always have different skills.
There's people that are very expert in something, and they like other
knowledge.
Otherwise, I take a decision. So you tell me.
Coffee time.
Okay.
I agree with that.
Of course, you do.
So we will have 15 minutes break, and then we will have the second part with
Julian. I will stop this recording.
Yes. You're welcome